<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cd on Amazon EKS Workshop</title>
    <link>/tags/cd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cd on Amazon EKS Workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/cd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Deployment with ArgoCD</title>
      <link>/intermediate/290_argocd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/intermediate/290_argocd/</guid>
      <description>Continuous Deployment with ArgoCD [Argo CD] (https://argoproj.github.io/argo-cd/) is a declarative, GitOps continuous delivery tool for Kubernetes. The core component of Argo CD is the Application Controller, which continuously monitors running applications and compares the live application state against the desired target state defined in the Git repository. This powers the following use cases:
Automated deployment : controller pushes the desired application state into the cluster automatically, either in response to a Git commit, a trigger from CI pipeline, or a manual user request.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Delivery with Spinnaker</title>
      <link>/intermediate/265_spinnaker_eks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/intermediate/265_spinnaker_eks/</guid>
      <description>Continuous Delivery with Spinnaker Spinnaker is an open-source, multi-cloud continuous delivery platform, originally developed by Netflix, that helps you release software changes rapidly and reliably. Development team can focus on just application development and leave ops provisioning to Spinnaker for automating reinforcement of business and regulatory requirements. Spinnaker supports several CI systems and build tools like CodeBuild, Jenkins. You can integrate Spinnaker for configuring Artifacts from Git, Amazon S3, Amazon ECR etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
